paulaschoice-eu.com 2019-07-07

# Privacy Policy

Paula's Choice Europe B.V. (“Paula’s Choice”) has prepared this privacy statement on how we collect, use and protect your (personal) data in order to show you that we are very serious about protecting your privacy.

In this statement, we inform you about how Paula’s Choice treats your personal data. This privacy statement applies to all personal data collected by Paula’s Choice for the online services we offer. In this context, Paula’s Choice Europe is regarded as the ‘Controller’ as defined in the Personal Data Protection Act and as ‘Controller’ as defined in the Dutch General Data Protection Regulation (‘AVG’).

If you visit our website, you automatically provide certain data. What information we receive from you and store depends on how you use the paulaschoice.nl website. You can read more about the following topics below:

  1. What personal data are processed, for what purposes, what legal basis is there for the processing and with whom do we share the data? 
    1. If you use the website;
    2. If you subscribe to the newsletter or request informational material;
    3. If you create an account and shop in our webshop;
    4. If you use our customer service;
    5. If you post a review of a product.
  2. How are your data protected?
  3. How long are your data stored?
  4. Access to, rectification and amendment of your data, and other rights you have;
  5. Contact details and amendments to the policy.

## 1\. What (personal) data are processed, for what purposes are the data used and with whom might they be shared?

Paula’s Choice records various (personal) data in the context of our service provision. What data are involved depends on how you use our website and/or webshop. You can use our website in the following ways:

  1. You only visit our website;
  2. You subscribe to our newsletter or request informational material;
  3. You create an account (and you shop in our webshop);
  4. You shop in our webshop without logging in/using an account;
  5. You shop in our webshop but do not finalise your order;
  6. You chat with us via the website;
  7. You give feedback or post reviews via our website;
  8. You use the customer service.

Below we describe for each type of use what data we process, why we do so, on what legal basis we process the data and with what other parties we might share the data. Without your permission, we never share your data with parties other than those mentioned below. We will also never sell your data to third parties.

### a. You only visit our website

Read about our [Cookie Policy](https://www.paulaschoice-eu.com/cookie-policy/cookie-policy.html).

### b. You subscribe to the newsletter or request informational material

If you subscribe to a newsletter from Paula’s Choice or ask us to send informational material, your personal data are used to inform you about our products and services. If you buy a product from Paula’s Choice and provide your data when doing so, for instance by asking a question, we may inform you about other Paula’s Choice products in the future.

You can always unsubscribe from the newsletter or mailing list by opting out or by contacting us at info@paulaschoice.nl.

**WHAT DATA**  
We process the following data:

  * First name and surname;
  * If you subscribe to the newsletter: email address;
  * If you request informational material: depending on how you request this and what you request: home/delivery address, telephone number, IP address, email address;
  * When subscribing to the newsletter, you can opt to fill in your date of birth and gender.

**FOR WHAT PURPOSE**  
Paula’s Choice uses your data for the following purposes:

  * To deliver the newsletter or informational material, on the basis of age and gender as well.

**WHAT LEGAL BASIS**  
When subscribing to our newsletter and/or requesting informational material, by opting in you unequivocally give permission for the processing of the above data so that we are able to deliver the newsletter and/or informational material. You have the right to revoke this permission at any time by simply sending an email to info@paulaschoice.nl.

**SHARED WITH WHOM**  
We share this information with:

  * The third parties that manage our mailing lists and send the newsletters;
  * The third parties we engage to deliver informational material.

### c. You create an account (and you shop in our webshop)

In order to place an order via our website, you can register yourself as a customer via paulaschoice.nl. You create an account that is protected by password and linked to your email address. You enter your data personally and can also change these yourself at any time by logging into your account.

**WHAT DATA**  
We process the following data:

  * First name and surname;
  * Home (delivery) address;
  * Email address;
  * Telephone number;
  * IP address;
  * What products you have viewed in the past 30 days;
  * What products you have ordered;
  * Your most recent visit and login are also recorded.

We do not process any payment data. Payments to our webshop are processed via a third party (our payment service provider: Adyen). Adyen offers a number of ways of paying securely. You enter your credit card or bank account details only on these secure pages and then complete your order here. We only receive from Adyen the message of whether your payment has been received, but not your credit card or bank account number. If you opt to pay via Klarna, the above also applies, but in addition to that, your date of birth is also recorded; this is needed in order to authenticate your payment. This information is shared with Klarna.

**FOR WHAT PURPOSE**  
Paula’s Choice uses your data for the following purposes:

  * We use the data you store in your account to process your orders - in other words, to perform the contract we have with you;
  * We use your IP address and information about your online behaviour to improve our online services, our products and your browsing experience. Our [Cookie Policy](https://www.paulaschoice-eu.com/cookie-policy/cookie-policy.html) contains more information on this, including information on how to refuse cookies.

**WHAT LEGAL BASIS**  
The processing of the data above is necessary in order to carry out your order - in other words, to perform the contract we have with you.

**SHARED WITH WHOM**  
We share this information with:

  * Our partners who prepare, ship and deliver the orders to you;
  * Our partners who improve your online shopping experience;
  * Our partners who handle the payment;
  * Our partners who provide the database that contains all the order data and customer data for our website.

### d. You shop in our webshop without logging in/using an account

You do not need to register as a customer in order to place an order via our website. You personally enter the data we need to carry out your order and can also change these data yourself at any time.

**WHAT DATA**  
We process the following data:

  * First name and surname;
  * Home (delivery) address;
  * Email address;
  * Telephone number;
  * IP address;
  * What products you have ordered.

We do not process any payment data. Payments to our webshop are processed via a third party (our payment service provider: Adyen). Adyen offers a number of ways of paying securely. You enter your credit card or bank account details only on these secure pages and then complete your order here. We only receive from Adyen the message of whether your payment has been received, but not your credit card or bank account number. If you opt to pay via Klarna, the above also applies, but in addition to that, your date of birth is also recorded; this is needed in order to authenticate your payment. This information is shared with Klarna.

**FOR WHAT PURPOSE**  
Paula’s Choice uses your data for the following purposes:

  * We use the data to process your orders - in other words, to perform the contract we have with you;
  * We use your IP address and information about your online behaviour to improve our online services, our products and your browsing experience. Our [Cookie Policy](https://www.paulaschoice-eu.com/cookie-policy/cookie-policy.html) contains more information on this, including information on how to refuse cookies.

**WHAT LEGAL BASIS**  
The processing of the data above is necessary in order to carry out your order - in other words, to perform the contract we have with you.

**SHARED WITH WHOM**  
We share this information with:

  * Our partners who prepare, ship and deliver the orders to you;
  * Our partners who improve your online shopping experience;
  * Our partners who handle the payment;
  * Our partners who provide the database for our website.

### e. You shop in our webshop and have logged in under your account, but do not finalise your order

If you put products into your shopping basket on our website but, for whatever reason, do not finalise your order, and you have provided your email address (for instance because you have logged into your account), we may help you to finalise this order. We do this by sending you an email with the products in your basket.

**WHAT DATA**  
We process the following data:

  * Email address;
  * Telephone number;
  * IP address;
  * What products you placed in your shopping basket but have not yet bought.

**FOR WHAT PURPOSE**  
Paula’s Choice uses your data for the following purposes:

  * We use the data you register to help you finalise your order either by email or by telephone;
  * We use your IP address and information about your online behaviour to improve our online services, our products and your browsing experience. Our [Cookie Policy](https://www.paulaschoice-eu.com/cookie-policy/cookie-policy.html) contains more information on this, including information on how to refuse cookies.

**WHAT LEGAL BASIS**  
The processing of the above data is necessary in order to investigate whether something went wrong in your order process.

**SHARED WITH WHOM**  
We share this information with:

  * Our partners who send the email reminding you about the contents of your shopping basket.

### f. You chat with us

If you remain on a webpage for a certain period of time, the chat functionality may start up. You can also start up the website chat functionality with Customer Care yourself if you have questions. You are asked to enter your name (or a fictional name to be used for you during the chat).

**WHAT DATA**  
We process the following data:

  * Your chat name;
  * optional) email address, if you provide this yourself;
  * IP address;
  * The length of your visit to our website.

**FOR WHAT PURPOSE**  
Paula’s Choice uses your data for the following purposes:

  * We use the data to be able to chat with you and advise on our products and the use of the website;
  * We use your IP address and information about your online behaviour to improve our online services, our products and your browsing experience. Our [Cookie Policy](https://www.paulaschoice-eu.com/cookie-policy/cookie-policy.html) contains more information on this, including information on how to refuse cookies.

**WHAT LEGAL BASIS**  
The processing of the above data is necessary to be able to chat with you and, if applicable, to provide you with advice on our products or the use of our website, in other words, to improve our service provision. If you personally provide us with data via the chat, such as your email address, for instance, you give your consent for this to be used for the purpose mentioned in this policy.

**SHARED WITH WHOM**  
We share this information with:

  * Our partners who provide the chat software that allows us to communicate with you.

### g. You give feedback or post reviews via our website

If you wish to post a review or give other feedback on our customer service or our products, you can do this on the website by logging into your customer account.

**WHAT DATA**  
We process the following data:

  * Your name (or the fictional name) you want displayed with the review;
  * Email address (we do not display this on the website with your review);
  * The feedback you provided or the content of your review;
  * The number of stars you gave our product.

**FOR WHAT PURPOSE**  
Paula’s Choice uses your data for the following purposes:

  * We use your name (or the fictional name you provided), the number of stars you have given us and your feedback or review to show our other customers what you think of our products and services;
  * We may also use the data to find a solution for a problem you may have raised.

**WHAT LEGAL BASIS**  
The processing of the above data is necessary to post your feedback or review on our website and, in that context, to contact you, if necessary, and find a solution for the problem or complaint you raise.

**SHARED WITH WHOM**  
We share this information with:

  * Our partners who manage the website;
  * Customer Care, who may be able to help you with a complaint.

### h. You use the customer service

If you contact us, for instance by asking customer service a question via info@paulaschoice.nl, telephone, social media or post, we use your personal data to respond to your question. We then register your question in our customer service administration.

**WHAT DATA**  
We process the following data:

  * First name and surname;
  * Depending on how you contact us: your telephone number, email address and/or home address.

**FOR WHAT PURPOSE**  
Paula’s Choice uses your data for the following purposes:

  * We use the data to improve our service provision;
  * We use the data to advise you in making selections in our webshop;
  * We use the data to assist you if you have questions or complaints about our products.

**WHAT LEGAL BASIS**  
The processing of the above data is necessary for advising you or assisting you with questions and/or complaints, depending on the reason you have contacted us.

**SHARED WITH WHOM**  
We share this information with:

  * Our partners who help us provide and perform our customer service.

## 2\. How are your data protected?

Paula’s Choice understands that storing your personal data securely is extremely important. The data stored in our database are protected via the usual electronic security techniques, in accordance with the applicable data security standards.

You can only access your account if you enter your email and password correctly. All sensitive information and passwords are protected by encryption and can never be viewed by us.

Our websites and web applications are secured by means of SSL certificates. You can see this from the green padlock icon to the left of the URL in your browser’s address bar. All data you send and receive via our website are therefore encrypted and cannot be read by third parties. The exchange of data between our websites and our processing partners also takes place via secure connections.

## 3\. How long are your data stored?

Paula’s Choice stores your data for no longer than permitted by law and no longer than necessary for the purposes for which your data are processed. How long certain data are stored depends on the nature of the data and the purposes for which they are processed.

## 4\. Access to and rectification of your data and other rights you have

### a. Access to, rectification and erasure of your data

If you so desire, Paula’s Choice can provide you with an overview of the personal data we have on file for you.  
If the information proves to be incorrect, or if storing the information emerges to be in violation of the legislation and regulations in effect, we will rectify this information or erase it at your request. Requests for access to data or the rectification or erasure of data can be submitted at any time by sending an email to info@paulaschoice.nl. After confirmation, Paula’s Choice will then erase or amend your data within 4 weeks.

### b. Objecting to data processing

If you do not agree with the processing of your data, you can object to the processing at any time by sending an email to info@paulaschoice.nl. After receiving your email, we will respond to your objection as soon as possible, but in any event within 4 weeks.

### c. Data portability

You are entitled to data portability. This means that you have the right to receive the personal data you have provided to us in a usable format so that they can be handed over to another controller. If you wish to receive your data in such a format, please send an email to info@paulaschoice.nl. We will contact you as soon as possible to discuss in what format you would like to receive the data. After this contact, we will respond to your request and provide the data within 4 weeks, and no later than within 3 months if the request is complex.

### d. Revoking permission granted earlier

If you have given us permission to process your personal data, you can revoke this permission at any time by sending an email to info@paulaschoice.nl. We will respond to and confirm your request in relation to revoking permission as soon as possible, but in any event within 4 weeks.

### e. Complain to a supervisory authority

Lodging a complaint with a data protection supervisory authority. If you have any concerns about our privacy practices, including the way we have handled your Personal Data, you can report it to the data protection authority that is authorized to hear those concerns.

## 5\. Contact details and amendments to the policy

If you wish to contact us with questions or comments about this privacy statement, you can do so via the contact details below:

Paula’s Choice Europe B.V.  
Telephone number: +31 (0)20 22 58 977  
Email address: info@paulaschoice.nl  
Postal address: Piet Mondriaanplein 29, 2812 GZ Amersfoort, The Netherlands 

Paula’s Choice may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time if new developments occur and/or it deems this necessary.
